Komal Bhandari (1) Featured

Senior Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Project Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Application Support, Apache Tomcat, Hibernate, Eclipse, HTML, Java, SQL, CSS



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Majesco Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Pune Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Computers]

Pref. Location: Ahmedabad, Mumbai, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Senior Software Engineer/Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Project

Management, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Requirement Gathering, Application

Support, Apache Tomcat, Hibernate, Eclipse, HTML, Java, SQL, CSS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

Aspiring to secure a challenging position with greater responsibilities where I can effectively contribute my skills and exercise my techno-functional knowledge in the field of software development.

Having 4+ Years of experience in Software Development.

Have experience in Java Development.

Proficiency in OOPS (Java).

Good debugging and problem-solving ability.

A team member with good communication and inter-personal skills. A dynamic quick learner with ability to work under extreme pressure and meet deadlines.

Work Experience

Majesco as Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2016 to Till Date

Majesco Ltd as Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2016 to Mar 2016

Project Name: BW Claims

Company Majesco Ltd.

Environment/Skills Core Java, JSP servlet, JQuery, Spring (MVC architecture), Hibernate, HTML, CSS, SQL, JS, Web

services.

Role Software Developer

Domain Insurance

Team Size 6

2016 - March 2020 Duration

Description:

Cover-all Claims Product customization

The Claims product is a solution provided to insurance companies to create and maintain customer claims against their policies for various lines of businesses. It has a core module to define business rules for different clients and SOA to connect to client's existing policy system. It also facilitates personnel hierarchy and authorization management.

Responsibilities for Product customization

Process inclusions:

- 1. Claim Setup
- Approval of setup as per the policy 2.
- Adding reserves
- 4. Make payments
- 5. Check generations
- 6. Close, reopen ,delete claims
- Reports Generation

Individual Responsibilities:

- Individual Contributor, server and database configuration, Design, Development, Technical notes preparation.
- Analysis, code and unit testing
- Conducting product training.

DP (defect prevention) analyst, do code review & prepare the code review check list specific to the Project & Business based on the learning's.

Skills Used: Core Java 6 & 7, Hibernate 5.1, Spring4, Jasper Reports, Oracle11g-12c,18c,MS SQL Server-2008, JAX-WS, XML, XSL, SVN, Eclipse, SoapUI, JBOSS 6 EAP

Project Name: Policy GAI 1)

Company Majesco Ltd.

Environment/Skills Core Java, Advanced java ,JSP servlet, JQuery, Maven, XML, XSL, HTML, CSS, SQL,JS, Web

services, Microservices

Role Software Developer Domain Insurance

Team Size 15+

Duration From April 2020

Description:

Policy GAI-Great American Insurance

The Policy product is a solution provided to American insurance company to create and maintain customer of Insurance against their policies/claims/billing for various lines of businesses. It also facilitates personnel hierarchy and authorization management.

Responsibilities for Product customization.

Individual Responsibilities:

- Individual Contributor, server and database configuration, Design, Development, Technical notes preparation.
- Analysis, code and unit testing
- Conducting product training.

DP (defect prevention) analyst, do code review & prepare the code review check list specific to the Project & Business based on the learning's.

Skills Used: Java 8, Oracle11g-12c,18c,JAX-WS, XML, XSL, SVN, Eclipse, SoapUI, Maven, Rest, Postman

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Electronics/Telecommunication) from shivaji university Kolhapur in 2014

PG: PG Diploma (Computers) from CDAC PUNE SUNBEAM in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Core & Advanced Java, Spring,	
Hibernate, JSP Servlet, SOAP,REST	
SQL Server, Oracle 12c, Oracle 18c	
HTML,CSS, Apache,ant, Maven	
Apache Tomcat, JBoss , Eclipse, Windows	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Marathi				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time